Welcome back to A push in under three
minutes. No time for intros, let's get
into it. So in this time period, finally
it is realized by American society that
the environment essentially exists. The
reason behind this is because a lot of
bad environment related things happen
all at once. This river, which I'm not
going to pronounce the name of,
literally caught on fire. This town was
built upon a bunch of toxic waste
causing a surge of diseases such as
cancer, and this power plant almost
completely melted down. And from all of
this, people start to realize industrial
growth just worse.
Of course, what I'm referring to here is
the energy crisis, where basically there
was severe fuel shortages in the Middle
East the US depended on, causing prices
at gas stations to spike and for there
to be historically long gas station
lines. This will all finally cause some
environmental action. Let's go through
some examples. The Environmental
Protection Agency will be created, the
Clean Air Act will limit emissions, and
the Endangered Species Act will protect
endangered animals/plants. As for
energy, the Department of Energy will be
created, and the US will shift to focus
more on energy independence. On the
screen now are AP style questions for
this topic. Pause now.
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
I will see you in the next one.